I am honored that the alliance
between Owari and Mikawa...
You're being far too formal.
Try to read the mood a little.
More importantly, Machiyo,
did you make sure the soldiers got a share?
Yes. Everyone was overjoyed.
They said that you were a splendid ruler.
Did they, now?
You can't fool me.
Taking out the Imagawa
barely got you any territory.
So you're keeping them sweet with food.
Quiet, you.
You'll be paying me back another way, got it?!
Wh-What are you after?
The prettiest girl in Japan!
You watching me from up there,
old man Toukichirou?
I'm on the path to becoming
a ladies' man as we speak!
Oda Nobuna no Yabou
The moment you swing the sword you pledged upon
You get hurt again
Biting down on my lip
I try to figure out what the right thing is
I will protect you, but before that
There's something I must do
I'm not trying to stand out
I just don't want to be a liar
I live on the battlefield with my life on the line
Whenever I look back, you're there to reassure me
The days of sorrow end, and the sun of ambition rises
Let's defeat fate and go as far as we want
Linking the world
Episode Five
Strategy of
the Genius Tactician
Episode Five
Strategy of
the Genius Tactician
Episode Five
Strategy of
the Genius Tactician
Episode Five
Strategy of
the Genius Tactician
We were already here!
I'm fairly certain we're following the Kiso River.
This doesn't feel right.
Shibata Katsuie's forces
are stuck in the swamp.
Them, too?
There are strange piles of stones
that are creating a labyrinth.
I saw something like this in a
Romance of the Three Kingdoms manga.
Romance of the Three Kingdoms?
The Stone Sentinel Maze!
Kongming's trap!
What's that?
This is a trap devised by the
brilliant strategist Zhuge Liang.
They're trying to lure us into the swamp
and then flood it with river water.
Goemon, destroy the stone piles!
Understood!
What are you doing, Monkey?
These are what're keeping us
trapped in the labyrinth, right?
So, let's destroy them all!
Someone down there has come up with an interesting idea.
You won't flood the area?
I won't.
My master prefers to avoid needless bloodshed.
After that, Oda advanced her forces to Mino,
but she lost every battle, with no
further success in her conquest.
This is so frustrating!
Why can't we win?!
Well, that's because-
There's a genius strategist in Mino.
Even I, the Viper, could not match his wisdom.
He's been called the greatest strategist in history.
He's a trillion times smarter than you morons!
Are you picking a fight?
I've never heard of any genius strategists.
Of course not.
He was Mino's greatest secret.
I will tell you.
His name is-
Takenaka Hanbei!
Anybody who plays Sengoku games knows him.
He has 98 points in INT, even without any item bonuses—
If you knew, then you should've
told me, you stupid monkey!
I only remembered after we fought him!
The question now is how to defeat Mino!
Well, yes, but...
Our only choice is to get
Takenaka Hanbei on our side.
It'd be faster to kill him.
You don't get it.
You need to get all the
top-ranked characters you can,
or you're gonna run out of good people later.
It's elementary in Sengoku games.
That said, Takenaka Hanbei is a man of honor.
I can't imagine he'd join the Oda.
A man of honor, and a kind man.
You're all still alive, aren't you?
Come to think of it, you're right.
He prefers to not shed blood needlessly.
Thus, I think he'd get along with our Nobuna.
He's wasted on Yoshitatsu.
As long as Takenaka Hanbei
is here, Mino is safe.
A greater genius than even Count Dousan.
Andou must be proud to be related to him.
No, not at all.
Well, maybe a little.
Why does Hanbei hide himself?
Does he dislike me, Yoshitatsu, that much?
Well...
He was a favorite of my father.
It's just that Hanbei prefers to hide himself...
I am his lord now!
What kind of retainer hides himself from his lord?!
Y-You're right!
So, who's bringing Hanbei in?
That'd have to be me.
Are you going to butt in again, Monkey?
This is my event.
Only Hideyoshi can win
Takenaka Hanbei over!
Who's Hideyoshi?
Never mind that.
Just leave it to me.
And more importantly,
once I've brought him back,
don't forget what you owe me.
Wh-What I owe you?
The prettiest girl in Japan, what else?!
I-I'm not that cheap.
You'd have to take over Mino, at least.
I know that's not happening.
I'll help you out, child.
You may have Mitsuhide as a guide.
Lookie here! No, you can't have it yet!
Sweetfish! Sweetfish!
Lookie, lookie. Okay, eat it!
I caught an Inuchiyo!
Why are you playing around?!
Has your rotten brain
forgotten your job already?!
Hey, calm down.
If you play Hideyoshi's route
in Legends of the Civil Wars,
Hanbei joins you.
Then surely you already know
that Takenaka Hanbei is an onmyouji.
Feels haunted.
It is!
That's why nobody comes here.
Hanbei's an onmyouji?
That's news to me.
Mitsuhide!
Andou Morinari!
I thought you were in
Owari with Count Dousan.
I see.
You've come to convince
Hanbei to join you.
Glad you understand.
We haven't been getting along
with Lord Yoshitatsu lately.
I should've gone with Count Dousan.
Then it's okay, right?
We are still retainers of
the Saitou family of Mino.
It will take more than
mere words to convince us.
A-Asai Nagamasa!
Monkey?
You again?
What are you doing here?!
I guess we're here for the same reason.
With Takenaka Hanbei at
my side, Mino will fall.
What the heck is this?
It's a wedding invitation Asai Nagamasa
sent to all the counts.
That was called off!
You still haven't given up?
If I give her Mino, Nobuna
won't be able to refuse.
The marriage is as good as done.
I told you already...
I won't give Nobuna to the likes of you!
Interesting.
So, it will be a showdown to see
which of us gets Takenaka Hanbei.
Sounds good to me.
I'd prefer you not decide that in my absence.
It's a ghost!
A pleasure to meet you.
I am Takenaka Hanbei.
I'm...
Monkey of the Owari Oda clan.
And the young count of northern Oumi,
Asai Nagamasa.
So you know all about us.
Then I'll get right to the point.
Join the Oda—
You were going to have a showdown, yes?
One of these is the correct one.
The first to eat it wins.
However, one of them is poisoned.
Poisoned?
Don't toy with us!
You get me, and Mino.
A prize worth more than your life.
That's not a good idea.
I promised her I wouldn't die!
S-Spicy!
Too bad. That was a hot pepper bun.
I won't lose!
A wasabi bun.
Two left.
Who gets it first?
I'm guessing black!
No, blue's the one!
That was a rock!
M-My teeth...
None of them were correct!
What fools.
There are ghosts here!
You tricked us!
It's your fault for being gullible.
I-Idiot!
Why did you kill him?!
Monsters are supposed to be exterminated.
You killed the Saitou family's strategist.
If this becomes known, Nobuna's
reputation will be ruined.
This is bad. Bring him back to life!
No response.
He already looks like a corpse.
He's just playing!
Wait. He's gone!
Where did he go?
Search him out!
Here!
Don't be mean to me.
Who are you?
I'm T-Takenaka Hanbei.
You're Takenaka Hanbei?
Yes. Um, please don't be mean to me.
I won't. I'd never be mean to such a cute girl.
I can't believe the Hanbei I looked up to
was just a little girl.
Zenki, please.
I am Hanbei's double, Zenki.
I have revived.
Double?
Indeed.
My master, Takenaka Hanbei,
was picked on because of her talents.
So, I took her place.
She's also very shy,
and she has a habit of deliberately
angering people to see how they'll treat her.
Will you be mean to me?
I won't be mean.
Bring me Hanbei!
Even though you command it...
You're saying you can't obey
orders from the likes of me?
You, too, must think that I'm
not half the man my father is!
N-Not at all!
Revolution has long been
part of Mino's history!
The strong take the land for themselves.
Hanbei plans to chase me from my
throne and have Mino for himself.
Lord Yoshitatsu, what are you...?
I'll listen to Hanbei's excuses.
Until then, you will go to prison.
Please wait, Lord Yoshitatsu!
Every last one of you is plagued
by the memory of Dousan's loss.
If Hanbei does not come, he will be executed.
A hostage?
That's really low.
If they're this serious...
You may be killed if you go.
What is Saitou Yoshitatsu thinking?
Without Hanbei, Mino is nothing.
He needs a sharp blade.
But too sharp a blade puts him at risk.
Yoshitatsu got cold feet.
Humans never change.
They only think about themselves.
Let Andou die.
If Andou dies, Hanbei will come to hate Yoshitatsu.
She will attack Inabayama Castle
to avenge her uncle.
Mino will belong to me and Nobuna-
Don't give me that!
I refuse to do anything
that would make a girl sad!
Andou is still safe.
I'm so glad.
Good work, Goemon.
I want you and Goemon to rescue Andou.
What will you do?
I'll buy time with Hanbei.
You're going to take her?
Not kid Hanbei. The other one.
I'll have Zenki take her place again.
No. I'll go.
It would be dishonorable
to deceive Lord Yoshitatsu.
But...
If I tell him the truth, that I'll never betray him,
he'll understand!
You're a very stupid person.
It isn't that easy.
I'm sure he will.
Fine. Let's go, then.
Mr. Yoshiharu?
I am Takenaka Hanbei.
Y-You are?
Impossible! Hanbei is a man!
I was using a double
for reasons of my own.
This little girl?
I refuse to believe it.
You've caught us by surprise.
You truly are a master strategist.
Um. My uncle...
When you are no longer suspected
of treason, I will return him.
I'd never betray you!
Those are just words!
I-I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
This is certainly unexpected.
You truly have no
intention of betraying me?
I do not.
In that case, why did you let the Oda go
despite having many
opportunities to destroy them?
I didn't want needless—
It is the job of a strategist
to decimate the enemy!
I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
Enough already!
You can kill the enemy,
but they'll just keep coming!
But what if the soldiers who run
speak of how terrified they were?
"Mino has a genius strategist."
"Attacking is useless."
Won't everyone realize that?!
And you say that was Hanbei's intention?
She let the enemy live, and won.
That's why she's a genius, right?
A strategist so powerful
is even more dangerous.
Takenaka Hanbei has no intention of rebelling.
She may not have the intention,
but she does have the capability.
That is her crime.
Petty...
You're far too petty!
What?
A true lord uses the best men
he can find to rule his country!
That was what Saitou Dousan did!
Why, you...
Kill them!
That crest... The Asai family?
Indeed. I am Asai Nagamasa.
Why is the young Count of Oumi here?
I...
Oda's Monkey was planning to
use Hanbei to assassinate you.
I came to stop them.
So, that's Nobuna's monkey?
You treacherous piece of filth!
You're the one who brought it to this!
Now I'll just have to join with Mino
and take Nobuna for myself!
You—
Sorry, but I'm not interested.
What?
Capture Nagamasa alive.
I don't care about the monkey.
Kill him.
So much for that little stunt.
Be silent!
Intruders!
Sagara, I've saved Andou!
Thank you, Goemon.
Nagamasa, we're leaving
with Hanbei.
Don't give me orders!
What are you going to
do with Hanbei?!
I won't kill her.
A lord makes use of the
best men he can find, yes?
I'll have Hanbei be my concubine,
so that she doesn't get any ideas.
C-Concubine?!
I need your power to surpass my father.
Together, we will conquer Japan.
Right, sweetie?
Run! Run away!
You can't leave me—
I'm taking back my master.
What?
Did we just... capture Inabayama Castle?
That is indeed what we've done.
Hanbei!
She's got a bad fever.
Th-This always happens when
I've used too many spells.
Hanbei!
Damn it!
What are you going to do?
We can't treat her here.
You'll abandon a castle you've captured?
I can't trade it for Hanbei!
Goemon, let's go!
Fool.
I'm sorry you had to do all this for me.
It's fine. Don't worry about it.
But if you'd just ignored me...
She wouldn't want to get the
castle like this, anyhow.
We'll go back and get it.
Just the way Oda Nobuna likes, fair and square.
She's a very important person to you, isn't she?
Well...
If she's that important,
then you should lead the
Oda clan and conquer Japan...
while hiding her somewhere safe.
That's not right.
I want to let her shine,
like the moon in the night sky.
She shines when she's trying to conquer.
If she stops being herself,
there's no point.
A bright light always casts a shadow.
And handling that is our job:
protecting her and letting her shine.
Th-That's just selfishness.
Every time you gain something,
you'll lose something.
You can't have everything.
Sure I can.
That's just being childish.
Then let me stay a child.
I don't want to lose anything.
You're a dummy, Mr. Yoshiharu.
Maybe I am.
Too big of a dummy for me to leave you alone.
I want to protect you, and let you shine, too.
Takenaka Hanbei will serve not the Oda clan,
but Sagara Yoshiharu.
Okay, my lord?
tada jidai no mannaka tatasarete tomadou toki ni
When I, lost in time, was standing there confused
te wo hiite kureta hito e dekiru koto sagashita
You pulled me through, so I wanted to do something in return
kizutsuki nagara warau sugata
You were smiling even though you were being hurt
kokoro no ura namida ga mieta
I saw you shedding tears deep inside
sukui motomeru koe kikitoreru no wa
I could only understand your call for help
yurusareta mono dake
When you opened up to me
kazoe kirenu arashi wo koete
I will overcome the countless storms
anata no yami saku hikari ni naru
And become the light that cuts through your darkness
mou mayowanai tomo ni ikitai
I won't hesitate anymore; let's go together
chikau yume ga donna mubou de atte mo
No matter how unrealistic our ambitions are
oboeteite shinjirareru basho wa
Remember there's a place you can believe in
koko ni aru to
Right here
Episode Six
Sunomata Castle